I started a business about 11 months ago.
In essence,
every day for the last 90 days,
I've averaged
$5,337 a day every day. And
today,
I'm going to tell you exactly how I do it
so you can rip me off and
steal it. Let's get into it.
So it's worth noting in
that $5,000 a day number,
I didn't even include the launch of the
business, which would be the most
fortuitous because it was new,
and it gave people the biggest discount to
join
then. So I created a business mentorship,
and to me that was Discord, which I would
spend at least an hour to two hours in a
day.
Video modules,
so people could understand how to build a
landing page, how to do a
squeeze page,
how to get people's email addresses,
what an email marketing campaign
looks like.
Then to help them with their branding,
how to position their business,
their pricing, how to create demand,
all the things that
are important to actually
running a business. Because
if you help someone just get more views on
social
media,
it doesn't mean they're going to trickle
down and actually have money in
their bank account at the end of it.
Even just little things like getting
people to get rid of three-month
commitment
periods,
get them to get rid of a money-back
guarantee.
In fact,
a lot of videos on this channel
are the exact kind of barriers that I
break down with people
when they start a business.
Then I was a little bit cheeky
and realized that there
were some modules that maybe
I hadn't gone into in enough detail.
So I added new courses, and this
is where stuff gets interesting.
One of the new courses
was because I saw that people
were majority making
short-form content.
So I created a brand new course
and called it Short Form
Content Mastery, and I thought,
you know what?
Let's position it at $99, which
is heinously underpriced.
But the moment that someone buys that,
straight away,
we send them an offer for the
business mentorship. Then again,
working with people in the Discord,
people going
through the modules, I've realized
that email marketing
was a much more complex
topic than maybe I'd given credit to.
So I created an email marketing course
called Email Advantage, and that was $199,
because that is a lot more profitable.
People making short-form content,
if you imagine this is a funnel,
top stage is
going to be content.
So it makes sense to charge people $99 to
make better
content.
People that have an issue with email
marketing, already a bit more
advanced.
They've probably got their content on
lock.
They've probably got emails,
or they're in the process of extracting
emails, or
they've got a bigger following,
but they don't know how to get those
people's email
addresses, which is what warrants
that bigger price.
Then if you think about it,
the business mentorship really sits here
because it
takes all of those components
and puts them together.
Now,
although I'm very proud of the business
mentorship, and we've got about 1,700,
maybe 1,800 people in that at the moment,
it's not the easiest thing to package
because pretty much everyone's got their
own mentorship.
Every single creator on social media
that's made a good income suddenly goes,
"Oh,
do you know what?
I could diversify my revenue stream.
And even though I do seven figures in my
fitness business, although my books and
events do seven figures,
I could have another seven-figure business
by telling
people how I did it." Which
is in essence what I'm doing.
You either die the hero
or live long enough to become the villain.
Now,
I would refer to these two as satellite
courses because although they're
included in the main price of the
mentorship, on their own,
they're great for
paid ads. Last month, about 45% of total
revenue, not sales,
was attributed to the short form content
creation course.
Email Advantage, I think, was about 15%,
and then about 40% was the business
mentorship.
But the interesting thing here
is it takes time.
Some people use this,
and a few days later, they purchase.
Same with Email Advantage. Now,
the other smart thing we do here is
if people do
want to join the business mentorship,
we deduct their initial investment that
they've already paid.
There's no point in double-charging them.
That just says, "Hey, I'm an asshole."
And as far as paid ads, we just keep
creating creatives,
doubling down on the ads that
are doing well, and pulling back
on the ads that don't do so well.
So what would be really interesting
is for me to
divulge the nuts and bolts of how it
is exactly we get people into the business
mentorship. And whilst explaining this,
I'm going to give you the principles of
how
I like to do business
and help people make more sales.
So if the business mentorship is here,
let's call that the purchase.
Let's actually say that's someone joining.
We need something
that sits just above that.
And for me,
it's got to be a good landing page.
And what I'll do is I'll leave a link in
the description where you can look at the
landing page.
And the landing page needs to do what it
is, why you need it, what
you get, why to trust you, how to buy.
Some people think
that a sales call sits between these two.
Absolutely not.
I do not need to call a chef of a
restaurant and talk to him for half an
hour
before I come to the restaurant
and spend hundreds of pounds.
I just need a good menu,
a decent Trustpilot score,
or feedback from
other people that I know that have been.
And ultimately, if I go
and it's a massive disappointment,
I'll kick up a fuss.
I'll put a conditional sales call here
only if you're desperate.
Or better yet,
pay someone else to do it
and give them 10%.
It's not worth your time, buddy.
So then okay,
how do we get people to the landing
page? Good question. My way, preferably,
that I like to do it is with a 30-day
autoresponder. Again,
there's a link in the description
that you can use.
Every day, I email someone
and blow their mind away with some kind of
bit of
business advice they maybe haven't
considered before.
Every day, same time,
without breaking stride, boom.
The exact time that they signed up,
they get boom, boom, boom, boom.
And by the end, on average,
between days 19 and 21, people join.
Now, although the sequence is 30 days,
they end up joining before the end of the
days. And that email sequence
is then split in two.
We have people that joined from paid ads
and organic.
Organic performs so much better. This
is why it's always good to be good
at content creation.
So many people seem to think
that they can just buy their way
out of getting good at creating content.
No. Even this idea for this video, me.
I know the cameras, the light,
and everything.
The reason that my paid ads perform well
is because I spent years mastering organic
content. And trust me, organic's better.
If you pay someone to arrive at your site,
it is not the same experience as having
someone follow you, like your content,
engage with it, interact with it.
Organic for the win. Organic is your cake,
paid ads is your sprinkle.
Then over a certain amount of time,
people end up going to the landing page.
Now,
what if for some reason they reach day 30,
no sale?
Well, what we do there
is we promote the short form content
creation
course. Because at some point,
getting them in there, whether paid
or organic,
has cost me time or money.
I've either paid in paid ads to get them
into the
funnel,
or I've worked my ass off for years making
organic content.
Either way,
if they've not bought after 30 days,
we'll take them here.
And although we make considerably less
money, that is much less
than what it costs to get them into this
funnel at the end of the day.
So even if they just join this to recoup
marketing costs, that is fine.
But let's not forget,
a lot of amount of people that do this,
they go, "Wow,
that was really good."
And they end up joining the business
mentorship.
And the reason I probably should have put
that to the landing page because they go
through an email marketing campaign.
Then we get to the top of funnel.
How do people get into this? Again,
socials.
At the time of recording this,
my main strategy looks like this.
YouTube Now, YouTube
is probably my biggest means of
acquiring leads at the moment. One,
people that use YouTube want to be
well-informed.
They're often your people
that give a shit, people that want to
do well,
people that want to understand how things
work.
They are the people
that aren't here to muck about.
I believe the YouTube audience
are just more tuned in to wanting to
be a better version, whether a business,
whatever it is.
I'm also a big believer
that people just need to spend a certain
amount of time in
front of you before they decide to do
business with you.
Let's say that amount is two hours.
If I use short-form content,
that could take me a long time to accrue
those
hours. But on YouTube,
someone might sit through a webinar
and end up watching a
few videos. So I think
when it comes to expending the amount of
money that you
would need to for business mentorship,
YouTube is the don.
Then YouTube, we also get clips,
and those clips
also make us paid ads.
So then we can run clips from the YouTube
content into paid
ads to get people into the 30-day
responder.
We also then have YouTube
that just has the link in the description,
because even
though some of you
are just going to try and rip this off,
you'll end up signing up
anyway,
and you'll end up in the responder.
This week, literally two days ago,
I created a jamessmith.business Instagram,
because then those clips can also come
here, find people on Instagram, and
again, I would then consider
that to be organic.
It's also worth noting that
if people don't buy the short-form content
creation
course, we will still try
and engage them into the email advantage.
And if they like that,
they'll also find their way into the
mentorship.
Keep in mind, if they do that,
they also get the short-form content
creation
course.
So although this looks absolutely chaotic,
we have the four-stage sales
system that I talk about so much.
We have Instagram socials.
We have some form of squeeze to get them
onto the 30-day autoresponder, whether
that's through paid ads or organic.
From there, they go through the sequence.
Days 19 to 21,
most people end up going to the landing
page and buying.
Maybe 2% of people go through to a sales
call, but I don't like them.
The landing page needs to know what it is,
why they need it, what they get, why
they trust you, how to buy.
Another key thing here, VSL.
VSL is a video sales letter,
and in essence, that
is a video where you just very
candidly explain to people why it is
that they need your course.
Doesn't have to be super polished,
doesn't have to be anything crazy in
particular.
Just talk to them.
Just make them feel like you're real
and that you care.
Similar to this video, in essence,
is some kind of VSL that
is existing up here in
the funnel.
Because you're spending this time in front
of me and because I'm doing
this all off the cuff
and explaining how my business works,
you are actually
migrating your way down here because I'm
trying to establish myself as an authority
and someone that knows what they're doing.
Because if I didn't know what I was doing,
it'd be very weird that I'd be making
five grand a day doing this.
Once you have that video sales letter,
it's just going
to get you sales into your end product.
There are some other things
that we tried as well.
We did a $1 course, theory being that
if someone was willing to
pay $1 for a course,
then they had a seven-day course, then we
would upsell them into the mentorship.
We've now discontinued that,
although on the launch of the $1 course,
we
made $10,000.
It was more so to test the psychological
impact.
If someone actually gives you a bit of
money, even for only $1, their payment
details are already in the system,
then it's just a click of the button to
get into
the business mentorship. Also,
rather than giving someone something for
free, which
is quite an exhaustive resource, for $1,
"Wow, I got that much value.
Imagine what I'd get for $99."
And although the $1 course performed well
compared to the other means and ways
that we're getting people into the
ecosystem,
we just had to drop it.
There's one last element to this that I'll
explain,
and some of you might have been in it.
You might not even know about it.
So for YouTube, occasionally, and soon,
we run webinars,
which are one hour-plus live streams.
Again, the reason I like live streams
is it's evident that I know what I'm
talking
about, or I wouldn't go fucking live.
Kamala Harris is going to lose the
election because she does not have the
ability
to make people understand or think
that she knows what she's on about.
Now, these webinars, we run signups to.
So we get emails from paid and organic.
We then send traffic to a live stream.
In that live stream, there
is often an offer and a link to a landing
page for that offer.
Often a bit different.
I'll do one for Black Friday.
But then we leave the webinar on YouTube
as an asset for people
to watch.
But then only about 15% of people
actually show up to the webinar,
even though they've signed up through paid
organic. And either way, those people,
even if they don't come, don't watch the
webinar, because we have their emails,
we still send them an offer.
How I'm averaging 5,000 US dollars a day
in just one of my businesses, so you can
copy it, right? Let's go back to the desk.
Hopefully, that was pretty interesting,
and if you want to check out the 30-day
sequence to see how good it is
or even just to get an idea of the
emotions that you would feel going through
that sequence so you can create one of
your own to put onto your own pages,
then I'll put a link in the description
below,
and you can check it out for yourself.
And if you're not interested in that,
well,
YouTube is going to recommend a video
and put it there,
and YouTube's pretty smart,
and it thinks you need to watch it,
so I'd watch it.